# Lori A. Smith

(864) 275-6564

lori.smith.25@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/lorismith25

### **Objective**

To use my professional and life experience skills to help an organization deliver higher quality products and excite customers leading to a great company with strong financials by supporting processes through the software development lifecycle.

### **Professional Experience**

Vice President, Charles Pinckney Elementary PTO - Voluntary Mount Pleasant, SC (Remote Position)

July 2011 - July 2013

- Provided leadership to board members, committee chairpersons, and parent volunteers in all areas, including event planning, fundraising, marketing, and membership
- Directed fundraising events generating \$100k per year, the highest ever, including Annual Oyster Roast (generated \$42k in revenue, expenses 17% under budget and record breaking attendance)
- Implemented electronic payments system for handling real-time payments of credit card and online transactions
- Managed PTO budgets and approval of all request and expenditures
- Collaborated with administrators, teachers, and executive board members to define and prioritize organization needs
- Drove social media marketing campaigns and maintained social media presence
- Created flyers, t-shirt and design assets needed for marketing, promotion and endorsement of events

## Social Media Marketing Director, Home Care Plus, LLC

July 2010 - December 2012

Mount Pleasant, SC (Remote Position)

- Created monthly newsletters using Constant Contact with a subscriber base of 1000+ contacts
- Authored press releases and managed PR process and inbound results using Google Analytics
- Designed and maintained Facebook, Twitter and LinkedIn presences' with multiple weekly posts
- Created and implemented an online marketing plan including social analytics
- Maintained and optimized website including SEO using WordPress
- Public presentations and business development for company and its services at community meetings

### Quality Assurance (QA) Analyst, Acadia HCS

October 2008-January 2009

- Columbia, SC (Remote Position)
  - Quality Analysis and manual testing of website and web applications
  - Documented and communicated release defects and enhancements daily to development team
  - Performed regression testing on corrected bugs
  - Worked with end users to gather, verify, document and resolve defects in production software

### Project Manager / QA Manager, UNC State-Chapel Hill, Office of the President Greenville, SC

July 2001 - February 2002

- Managed project and daily tasks of development team consisting of more than 5 individuals using XP
- Worked with customers and Subject Matter Experts (SME) to obtain, verify and document business requirements
- Organized and lead team weekly status meetings, met with upper management to discuss progress
- Developed Institutional Subsystem using J2EE, Struts, HTML and JavaScript
- Managed team in Quality Assurance of application; including unit, functional and stress testing
- Tracked defects, issues, risks and dependencies, resolving with developers, customers and upper management

### Programmer / Analyst, Kyrus Corporation Greenville, SC

November 2000 - July 2001

- Developed application to setup all necessary information in order to run the FuelPath application in convenient stores. This application remained in the stores to be used by the store managers to change the various settings to run the fuel dispensers. Also, maintained the database for the FuelPath system
- Use case development & requirements analysis
- Prototype Design, application development using Java & Swing, & maintained database

Lori A. Smith 1

- Participated in the development of the Rockwell B2B e-commerce website using BroadVision technologies. Created a Java application to be used for Quality Analysis. This was a short 5-month deployment
- ♦ Java application development
- ♦ Worked with BroadVision's components, Quality Analysis of the website

# Business Analyst Team Lead, Metropolitan Life Insurance

November 1997 - August 1998

- Utica, NY

  A Lead the Auto Home and Dental Subject Matter Experts (SME) in
  - ◆ Lead the Auto, Home and Dental Subject Matter Experts (SME) in the development of the Customer Service Workstation. This reengineering project was the focus of all lines of business to design one common front-end system, which encompassed the system needs of all product lines while streamlining the processes
  - ◆ Lead User Interface (GUI) design meetings

### Business Analyst, Metropolitan Life Insurance

November 1996 – November 1997

Utica, NY

- Designed the Auto/Home workstation for the Customer Service Department. This workstation had to meet all the business needs as well as support the Service Level Agreement for maintaining call volume in the call center
- Use Case Driven Analysis, Process Flow Diagrams, Data Templates and Screen Mappings
- ♦ Managed User Acceptance Testing (UAT)

# Software Help Desk Specialist, Metropolitan Life Insurance Utica, NY

March 1991 - November 1996

- ♦ The Computer Consultants provided support to the sales force by resolving computer problems and providing training. The small team operated on a toll-free number in order to provide convenience as well as quality customer service to our agents throughout the country
- Developed and presented training materials on software products for field agents
- Performed QA testing on Point of Sale (POS) software
- ♦ Analyzed, diagnosed, and fixed software problems with field agents

### **Technical Skills**

Operating Systems: OS X, MS Windows, Unix, Internet, Mobile

Databases: Access97, Sybase, Interbase

Java Technologies: JDK 1.2/1.3, J2EE, JSP, Struts, Swing, JBOSS, WebLogic 6.0

Internet: BroadVision 4.1 One-To-One ES, HTML, CGI Scripts, FrontPage, Dreamweaver, Word Press

QA Tools: eTest, JUnit, HttpUnit, EzTrack, PVCS Tracker, Manual Test Plans, Bugzilla

Other Languages: JavaScript, C, COBOL, Perl, SQL

Software: Use Case, UML, Java, Visual SourceSafe, PVCS, UltraEdit

Business Apps: Microsoft Project, Visio, Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Google Apps, Dropbox

Marketing: Constant Contact, SurveyMonkey, Facebook Analytics, Google Analytics, Publisher, Blogger

#### Education

Bachelor of Science
Computer Information Systems

State University of New York Institute of Technology, Utica, NY

Associates of Applied Science
Accounting and Finance

Mohawk Valley Community College, Utica, NY

2

# **Certifications / Courses**

- Practical Guide to Agile Extreme Programming
- Web Design & Internet Programming
- Social Media Across Multiple Platforms
- Database Management Systems
- ♦ Online Software Documentation
- ♦ Java2 Certification Course

Lori A. Smith